

# BENJAMIN SOLT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Engineer who is eager to grow and learn new programs.

Prior experience includes 10 years in retail, developing skills in teamwork, communication, and customer service.

Took initiative to self teach Epic Game's Unreal Engine.

#### **SKILLS**

- CSS
- Adobe Creative Suite
- HTML
- Unreal Engine • 3D Studio Max JavaScript
- React
- Python
- Redux

# **EDUCATION**

#### LAMBDA SCHOOL - REMOTE

July 2019 - Present Full Stack Web Developer

# **TEMPLE UNIVERSITY CERTIFICATION IN WEBSITE DESIGN**

May 2012

- Intensive course focused on creative web design
- page layouts and art assets
- Utilized HTML, CSS, and Dreamweaver

### THE ART INSTITUTE OF PHILADELPHIA

December 2007

• Bachelor of Science Degree in Media Arts and Animation

#### **CONTACT INFO**

- Bensolt@gmail.com
- Cell: 215 360 5410
- Fort Washington, PA
- Bensolt.com
- LinkedIn
- Github

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **PORTFOLIO**

<u> APRIL 2020 - PRESENT</u>

Built to showcase personal projects HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React

• Designed, developed and implemented React based site to display a diverse range of personal projects

## GROA - FRONT END DEVELOPER

FEBRUARY 2020

Built to recommend movies to user, based on how user rates movies HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React | AWS

- As Front End Developer built Authorization, Login, display layout of movie info
- Solved problems and trouble shot bugs with team members
- Collaborated remotely with team of 6 web developers, 2 data science, and 1 UX designer

#### REACT-REDUX-APP2

DECEMBER 2019

Built to demonstrate API call and Redux HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React | Halo API

- Implemented Halo API database to visualize data from site
- Built a filter to allow a user to search by name of player

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## LOGO AND ART ASSET DESIGNER

WILLOW GROVE, PA

NOVEMBER 2013 - PRESENT

- Created logos and t-shirt graphics, to meet various companies contracted needs
- Designed art assets to display instructional steps and enable end users to envision system process
- Animated, modeled and textured 3D art assets to visually show and document how the system works
- Created 3D rotation of a medical device to share with internal and external stakeholders

## PRODUCE ASSOCIATE - FRESH MARKET/GIANT

HORSHAM, PA

NOVEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2019

- Restock produce and ensure available products are fresh daily
- Respond to shopper inquiries, assist with locating specific products and provide overall friendly customer service